[

Bring joy to a musician Thomann Gift Cards Thomann Gift Cards Shop now

Shop now](https://www.thomann.de/intl/basket_coupon.html)

search  

en · $

* Products
* Service
* About Us

Our added values

Information about Thomann

Our Specialist Departments

Fine Print

Customer Centre login

Country and Language

Energy Efficiency Class

Specifications for the charging function and the compatible chargers

Privacy Notice
==============

This Privacy Notice describes how Thomann GmbH (hereinafter also referred to as “Musikhaus Thomann”) processes and protects according to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the relevant German data protection laws, in particular the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG), the data you provide us with when using our website.

The security of personal data such as name, address, telephone number or email, is a serious and important concern for our company. Therefore, we conduct our online activities in compliance with the respective statutory provisions relating to data protection and data security. Below, you can find the information we process.

#### **Responsible authority, contact person for queries or exercising your rights as a data subject, contact**

The responsible authority within the meaning of the data protection regulations for all data processing through the Musikhaus Thomann website is:

**Thomann GmbH, Hans-Thomann-Strasse 1, 96138 Burgebrach, Germany**

In the event of any questions, comments, complaints or to exercise your rights as a data subject in connection with our Privacy Notice and the processing of your personal data by Musikhaus Thomann’s websites, you can contact Musikhaus Thomann’s Data Protection Officer directly by email ([privacy@thomann.de](mailto:privacy@thomann.de)). They will gladly take care of your data protection concerns.

#### **Personal data / types of use**

As a principle, the protection of your personal data is of highest priority for Musikhaus Thomann. You decide whether or not you wish to make such data known to us, for example in the course of any registration, survey or the like. Such information on your part is relevant for your enquiry, but you provide it on a voluntary basis. An exception to this rule is when prior consent cannot be obtained for practical reasons and the processing of data is permitted by law.

####   
**Legal basis for the processing of personal data**

If we obtain the consent of the data subject to process their personal data, Article 6(1)(a) GDPR serves as the legal basis for the processing of personal data.

When processing personal data necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party, Article 6(1)(b) GDPR shall serve as the legal basis. This also applies to any processing required to perform pre-contractual measures.

If processing of personal data is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which Musikhaus Thomann is subject, Article 6(1)(c) GDPR shall serve as the legal basis.

In the event that the vital interests of the data subject or of another natural person necessitate the processing of personal data, Article 6 (1)(d) GDPR shall serve as the legal basis.

If processing is necessary to safeguard the legitimate interests of our company or of a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject, Article 6(1)(f) GDPR shall serve as the legal basis for processing.

Should we access your device and the information stored there or should we save information on your device as part of our processing (e.g. by using cookies), the primary legal basis is § 25(1)(1) TTDSG if we require your consent for this access, or § 25(2)(2) TTDSG if the access concerns processing that is technically absolutely necessary.

####   
**Data deletion and storage duration**

The data subject’s personal data will be deleted or blocked as soon as the purpose of storage ceases to apply. Data may be stored beyond this if provisions have been made for this by the European or national legislator in Union regulations, laws or other rules to which the controller is subject. Data will also be blocked or deleted if a storage period prescribed by the standards mentioned above expires, unless there is a need for further storage of the data for the conclusion or fulfilment of a contract.

#### **Exchange of data / contractual relationships with partners / third parties**

In addition to the types of use described above, Musikhaus Thomann will transfer your data to third parties that are involved in the processing of your order or that participate in contracts. For example, if you place an order via our website, we will transmit your order information to Musikhaus Thomann’s partner companies and contractors who process and deliver your order to you. Data will only be transmitted to the extent required in order to fulfil or deliver your order or to process an enquiry. The legal basis for this is the fulfilment of the contract concluded with you (e.g. for orders) or the initiation of a contract (Article 6(1)(b) GDPR).

Furthermore, when shipping such goods with a value that exceeds the insured liability limit of the shipping company appointed by us, we will pass on the type and value of the goods as well as the name and address of the recipient of the goods to our supplementary transport insurance provider. We do this in our legitimate interest, in particular to protect our goods from accidental loss or damage in transit. Without this supplementary transport insurance, we would not be able to ship higher-priced goods. We have contractually obligated the insurance company to adhere to the designated purpose and maintain confidentiality, and to process the transmitted data exclusively for the purpose of processing an insurance claim. The legal basis for this is Article 6(1)(f) GDPR.

We will also transmit personal data to third parties where we are required to do so by law. The legal basis in this instance is Article 6(1)(c) GDPR.

####   
**Data automatically collected on our website / usage data**

We welcome everybody to visit and use our website free of charge and to look at the products on offer. When you visit our website, we record the following general usage data in order to assess which parts of our website you visit and how long you stay there:

1. Information about the browser type and version used
2. The user’s operating system
3. The user’s IP address
4. Date and time of access
5. Websites from which the user’s system reaches our website
6. The services and functions used on our website

Such data will be combined with the usage data of all visitors to our website in order to measure the number of visitors, the average time of the visits, pages visited, etc. The data we collect is combined and used for internal purposes only.

The legal basis for the temporary storage of data and log files is Article 6(1)(f) GDPR.

We use this combined data for evaluating our products, services and the news we make available via our website, as well as for monitoring use of our website and generally improving its content.

The temporary storage of IP addresses by the system is required in order to enable the delivery of the website to the user’s computer. To do this, the user’s IP address must be stored for the duration of the session.

Data is stored in log files to ensure the functionality of the website. In addition, we use the data to optimise the website and to ensure the security of our information technology systems. These purposes are also the basis for our legitimate interests in data processing pursuant to Article 6(1)(f) GDPR.

The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. If data is stored in log files, this is the case after no more than seven days. Further storage is possible. In this case, the users’ IP addresses are deleted or distorted, so that it is no longer possible to associate them with the calling client.

The collection of data in order to provide the website and the storage of the data in log files is essential for the operation of the website. Therefore the user cannot opt out.

Third party advertisements or links to other websites displayed on our website may collect user data if you click on them or otherwise follow their instructions. We have no control over the data collected either voluntarily or involuntarily via advertisements or websites of third parties. We recommend that you read the privacy policies of the promoted websites if you have any concerns regarding the collection and use of your data.

####   
**Cookies**

Like many other commercial websites, Musikhaus Thomann sometimes uses the technology known as “cookies” to collect information on how you use the website, and to ensure your visit runs smoothly.

Cookies are text files that are stored in the Internet browser or come from the Internet browser on the user’s computer system. When a user visits a website, a cookie may be stored on the user’s operating system. This cookie contains a distinctive string that allows the browser to be uniquely identified when the website is visited again.

**Cookies cannot read any information from your computer or interact with other cookies on your hard disk. However, cookies enable us to recognize you when you revisit our website. You can find the data that has been stored in cookies in the cookie settings.**  
Our website makes use of transient cookies, persistent cookies, tracking/web bugs and local storage.

**_Transient and persistent cookies_**

**Transient cookies** are automatically erased when you close your browser. In particular, these include session cookies. These store a “session ID” with which various requests from your browser can be assigned to the joint session. This enables our website to recognise your computer when you return. Sessions cookies are erased when you close your browser.

We use transient cookies to make our websites more user-friendly. Some elements on our website require the browser to be identified even after you have moved to a different page.

Our website also uses **persistent cookies** that enable analysis of the browsing behaviour of our users. Persistent cookies are automatically erased after a prescribed period, which may vary depending on the cookie. They enable transmission of, for example, IP addresses and search terms entered, as well as the use of certain website functions.

Most cookies do not save a user’s personal data. However, the user’s email address and customer ID could be stored on the server in addition to the cookie ID.

**_Tracking/web bugs_**

Some of our services also use “tracking bugs”, “web bugs” or “tracking pixels”. This involves code snippets that are usually only 1x1 pixel in size and can identify and detect your browser via the browser ID – your browser’s individual “fingerprint”. These enable the service provider to see how many users have accessed the pixel and if and when an email has been opened or a website has been visited.

You can use tools such as webwasher, bugnosys and AdBlock to prevent web bugs on our website. We will not use web bugs to secretly collect your personal data or share such data with third parties and marketing platforms without your express consent.

**_Purposes of and legal basis for the use of cookies and other identifiers_**

The legal basis for processing personal data using technically necessary cookies is § 25(2)(2) TTDSG for the setting of such cookies on your device, as well as Article 6(1)(1)(f) GDPR, e.g. for any subsequently necessary processing on our systems.

The purpose of using technically essential cookies is to facilitate the use of websites for users. Some features of our website cannot be provided without the use of cookies. For these features, it is necessary to recognise the browser, even after moving to a different page.

The right to object is excluded for technically essential cookies as these are required to display the website and its contents and to make the functionalities of the website available to you.

The user data collected through technically necessary cookies is not used to create user profiles.

Analysis and marketing cookies are used to improve the quality of our website and its contents. Analysis cookies allow us to ascertain how the website is used and thus constantly optimise our service. To perform processing functions on your end device that are based on cookies or other identifiers (e.g. browser fingerprints, pixels) and are not technically necessary for our website to function, we first require your consent, which you can give using the cookie pop-up that appears when you access our website. The legal basis for this cookie-based processing is § 25(1)(1) TTDSG for the setting of cookies on your device, and Article 6(1)(a) GDPR for the subsequent processing outside of your device on our systems or the systems of our technology partners. These types of cookies are not necessary for our website to function and will not be placed until you give your consent.

* * *

#### **Withdrawal of consent to the use of cookies and other identifiers/tags**

**_You can at any time withdraw your consent to the use of cookies to collect data by deactivating cookies_** [**here**](https://www.thomann.de/gb/cookie_configuration.html?scope=full)**_. You can also deactivate cookies individually or entirely using the toggle switch in the cookie settings. You can decline cookies that are not technically necessary directly via our cookie layer the first time you visit our website._**

**_If you do not want your browser to accept cookies, you can also deactivate or restrict cookies. Cookies that have already been saved can be deleted or deactivated at any time in your web browser. Deactivation of cookies may prevent this website from functioning properly. You may not be able to access all the options and information on this website. Please remember that cookies must be deactivated separately in each of the browsers you use._**

**_For more information about how to manage or delete cookies using the settings in your browser, please visit the help page for that browser._**

* * *

#### **Registration**

On our website, we offer users the opportunity to register by providing their personal data. The data is entered into an input screen and sent to us and stored. Data is not transferred to third parties. The following data is collected during the registration process:

1. First name and surname
2. Address
3. Email address
4. Company/institution/band (optional)

As part of the registration process, consent is obtained from the user to process this data.

The legal basis for processing data if the user’s consent is given is Article 6(1)(a) GDPR.

If the registration serves to fulfil a contract to which the user is party or to perform pre-contractual measures, the additional legal basis for the processing of data is Article 6(1)(b) GDPR.

User registration is necessary in order to provide certain content and services on our website.

User registration is necessary in order to fulfil a contract with the user or to perform pre-contractual measures.

The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection.  
This is the case for data collected during the registration process if the registration for our website is cancelled or modified.

This is the case for data collected during the registration process for the purpose of fulfilling a contract or performing pre-contractual measures if the data is no longer necessary for the performance of the contract. Even after the conclusion of the contract, there may be a need to store the contracting party’s personal data in order to comply with contractual or legal obligations.

As a user, you have the option to cancel your registration at any time. The data stored about you can be modified at any time via customer support or the customer centre.

If the data is necessary for the fulfilment of a contract or for performing pre-contractual measures, premature deletion of the data is only possible if contractual or legal obligations do not preclude deletion.

#### **Contact form and email contact**

Our website offers options to give feedback, to use live support and to leave notes/comments for orders. If a user takes advantage of one of these options, the data entered on the input screen will be transmitted to us and stored. This data includes:

1. “Give feedback”: your message (if it contains voluntary information from you containing personal data), and email address (optional)
2. Live support and notes/comments on orders: only data that is required for your individual support request or that you voluntarily provide in your note/comment

Alternatively, you can contact us via the email addresses provided on our website. In this case, the user’s personal data transmitted by email will be stored.

No data is passed on to third parties in this context. The data is used exclusively for processing the conversation.

The legal basis for processing the data transmitted in the course of sending an email is Article 6 (1)(f) GDPR. If the purpose of the email is to conclude a contract, the additional legal basis for the processing shall be Article 6(1)(b) GDPR.

The personal data from the input screen is only processed in order for us to process the contact. In the event of contact via email, this is also the basis for the required legitimate interest in the processing of data.

Any other personal data processed during the sending process serves to prevent misuse of the contact form and to ensure the security of our information technology systems.

The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. For the personal data from the contact form input screen and the data sent by email, this is the case if the respective conversation with the user has ended. The conversation is deemed to be ended if it can be inferred from the circumstances that the relevant facts have been conclusively clarified.

#### **Email newsletter – registration, subscription, performance and reach measurement**

**Newsletter registration and subscription**

Our website offers you the opportunity to subscribe to free promotional emails and to subscribe to our email newsletter, among other things. Only your email address will be used for this purpose. The following technical usage data is also collected when you sign up:

1. IP address of the accessing computer
2. Date and time of subscription to the newsletter

We use your data in order to send you the newsletter by email. Your consent for data processing for the purpose of sending the newsletter will be obtained and a reference will be made to this Privacy Policy during the sign-up process so that the data can be processed. The legal basis for this is Article 6(1)(a) and Article 7 of the GDPR, and § 7(2)(2) of the German fair trade law (UWG).

The collection of further data as part of the sign-up process serves to prevent misuse of services or of the email address provided during sign-up.

The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. As such, the data collected for sending emails will be stored for as long as the subscription to the promotional emails is active, i.e. until unsubscription. The exception to this is your email address, which we will add to our block list after unsubscribing from promotional emails. In this case, the processing of your email address is justified under Article 6(1)(f) GDPR and the legitimate interest in this processing lies in the protection of your interest in not receiving further promotional emails from us. Therefore, your email address will not be deleted, but its processing will be restricted in accordance with Article 18 GDPR.

The newsletter is sent on our behalf via the Sendgrid service of the provider Twilio Germany GmbH, Rosenheimer Str. 143C, 81671 Munich (processor, hereinafter referred to as “Twilio”). We have contractually obligated Twilio via a data processing agreement to comply with data protection and to implement appropriate technical and organisational measures. As part of the data processing, Twilio receives the newsletter data as a recipient in order to deliver the newsletter and to provide us with further services, e.g. to analyse the newsletter click behaviour (see section below on _Performance and reach measurement via the newsletter_).

* * *

#### **Statutory right of withdrawal**

**You can withdraw your consent to receive the email newsletter at any time. A corresponding link can be found in every email, which you can use to unsubscribe from the newsletter.**

**This also allows you to withdraw the consent to storage of the personal data collected during the sign-up process.**

* * *

**Performance and reach measurement via the newsletter**

The promotional emails sent contain a pixel that transmits information to us as soon as you open the newsletter. We subsequently retrieve this information in order to generate statistical analyses and to measure the success of our email campaigns. The information is as follows:

* Your IP address
* Information on the browser used
* Information on the system used
* Time of access

This information enables us to determine whether newsletters are opened, at what time they are opened and which links are clicked in these emails. It is technically possible to identify individual email recipients here; however, this is not used to track or monitor each user individually. We only use the analyses to tailor our email content to the wishes and interests of our newsletter subscribers based upon their reading habits, and to personalise it within the legal limits.

We use both Sendgrid and Google Analytics for the aforementioned evaluation and analysis (see section on Google Analytics).

The legal basis for data processing for the above analysis purpose is also your consent in accordance with § 25(1)(1) TTDSG for access to your device, and in accordance with Article 6(1)(1)(a) and Article 7 GDPR for the subsequent processing outside of your device on our systems or the systems of our technology partners Twilio and Google.

* * *

#### **Statutory right of withdrawal**

**When withdrawing your consent to receive the email newsletter, you can simultaneously withdraw your consent to the processing of your data for the purposes of performance and reach measurement.**

* * *

#### **Userlike Chat**

Our website uses Userlike, a service of Userlike UG (limited liability), Probsteigasse 44–46, 50670 Cologne, Germany (hereinafter “Userlike”). Asour technology partner, we have contractually obligated Userlike UG to comply with data protection requirements when processing personal data on our behalf via a corresponding data protection agreement.

Userlike allows you to start a live chat and contact us via the widget embedded on our website. In this case, we will process the following data:

* Communication content of the chat
* Date and time of chat
* Name of our employee with whom the chat is conducted
* Chat language
* Duration
* Starting URL from where the chat was started
* Destination URL where the chat ended
* IP address

The data will be processed exclusively for the purpose of chat communication.

The legal basis for processing data if the user’s consent is given is Article 6(1)(a) GDPR. You can give and revoke your consent via our cookie layer. If you revoke your consent during an ongoing chat, we will not be able to continue the chat and will terminate it.

We use the technical usage data we process during a live chat to prevent misuse of the chat and to ensure the security of our IT systems. This is in our legitimate interest in accordance with Article 6(1)(f) GDPR.

You can find more information in the Userlike Privacy Policy: [https://www.userlike.com/en/terms#privacy-policy](https://www.userlike.com/de/terms#privacy-policy).

The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. The data we process during the live chat will be deleted after one month at the latest.

#### **Contact and customer support via WhatsApp**

You can contact us via WhatsApp at any time, e.g. for questions about order processing or our products or other customer support issues. We facilitate this by including a click-to-chat link to WhatsApp in the chat area on our website and by providing our WhatsApp contact number in the relevant section in customer communication and on our website. We will only ever contact you via WhatsApp at your express request, i.e. only if you contact us and start communicating with us via WhatsApp.

By initiating communication via WhatsApp and sending us a WhatsApp message with your request to our WhatsApp contact number, you agree to these data protection provisions and simultaneously consent, in accordance with Article 6(1)(a) GDPR, to your personal data (surname and first name, telephone number, messenger ID, profile picture if applicable and message history) being processed in the context of this usage of WhatsApp to send messages to you. Messages sent via WhatsApp are end-to-end encrypted. This means that the content of the sent message is only visible to the sender and the recipient. WhatsApp has no access to the sent messages. An active WhatsApp account is required to use WhatsApp.

The communication takes place via the WhatsApp Messenger service of WhatsApp Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland. WhatsApp cannot view the content of the messages sent, but can at any time determine that you have communicated with us and when this communication took place, and can obtain technical information about the device you are using. You can find more information on how WhatsApp handles your data and what security requirements WhatsApp has implemented to protect communications in the details of our WhatsApp communication or by visiting [https://faq.whatsapp.com/general/security-and-privacy/end-to-end-encryption-for-business-messages](https://faq.whatsapp.com/general/security-and-privacy/end-to-end-encryption-for-business-messages).

Our WhatsApp for Business account is provided by 360dialog GmbH, Torstrasse 61, 10119 Berlin, Germany, and is connected via a technical interface to our chat environment and to the communication dashboard used internally by our customer support. As our technology partner, we have contractually obligated 360dialog GmbH to comply with data protection requirements when processing personal data on our behalf via a corresponding data protection agreement. Even when the processing of personal data on our behalf is not covered by the contract, the possibility of 360dialog GmbH accessing personal data when providing our WhatsApp for Business account is not technically excluded.

You are always free to revoke your consent to the processing of personal data. To do so, simply notify us of this, e.g. by sending an email to [privacy@thomann.de](mailto:privacy@thomann.de). As a rule, we delete the data we receive from you via WhatsApp as soon as we have answered the questions asked via WhatsApp and no further queries or messages are expected from you. Longer storage periods may occur if the transmitted message content results in an obligation to store the data due to statutory retention obligations. For more information, please refer to the respective privacy policies of [WhatsApp](https://www.whatsapp.com/legal/business-policy/) and [Userlike](https://www.userlike.com/de/terms#privacy-policy).

The WhatsApp privacy policy also states that WhatsApp may process your data outside the EU. However, this does not apply to the communication content, only the technical metadata that is created during communication. This data includes, but is not limited to, your phone number, device, type and time of use, location and IP address. Please be aware that you have already consented to this processing by accepting WhatsApp’s privacy policy when you set up your WhatsApp account and used WhatsApp for the first time.

#### **Use of services for marketing and analysis purposes**

#### **Google Analytics**

Our website utilises Google Analytics, a web analytics tool by Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, text files stored on your computer that enable analysis of how you use the website. The cookie-generated information about your use of this website is usually transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the United States. However, if you are in a country that is a member state of the European Union or a contracting party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area, and if IP address anonymization has been activated on this website, Google will first truncate your IP address. Only by way of exception will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the United States and truncated there. Google will use this information on our behalf for the purposes of analysing how you use the website, compiling reports on website activity and providing further services related to website and internet use to the website operator. Google will not combine the IP address transmitted by your browser via Google Analytics with other Google data. You can disable cookies by setting your browser accordingly; however, if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. Furthermore, you can prevent collection and transfer of the data generated by cookies on [www.thomann.de](http://www.thomann.de/) and relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) to Google, as well as the processing of such data by Google, by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under the following link: [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/eula.html?hl=en](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/eula.html?hl=en).

* * *

#### **Statutory right of withdrawal**

**You can find out how to withdraw your consent given using our cookie pop-up in the section _Withdrawal of consent to the use of cookies and other identifiers/tags._**

* * *

We would also like to point out that our website uses Google Analytics with the anonymizeIP extension so that IP addresses are only processed further in an abbreviated form to prevent them being directly linked to a particular individual.

More detailed information about the function of Google Analytics and the terms of use and privacy policy relevant to this service can be found under [http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html) and [http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

Google Ireland Ltd. is a subsidiary of Google LLC, based in the USA. It cannot be excluded that the data collected by Google will also be sent to the USA.

#### **Google Tag Manager**

We use Google Tag Manager to manage “website tags”. Tags are small code elements on our website that run upon certain interactions with the website and send measured data to the third party programs used (e.g. Google Analytics). The Tag Manager itself does not use cookies and does not collect any personal data. The Tag Manager triggers other tags that collect data and place cookies under certain circumstances (e.g. the third party programs used). The Tag Manager does not access this data.

#### **Facebook Remarketing**

Our website uses the “Vanilla Custom Audiences Pixel”, a service provided by Meta Platforms Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2 Ireland (“Facebook”). With the help of this service we can reach our customers directly through the Facebook network by showing “Facebook ads” to visitors of our website when they visit the social network Facebook.

To this end we have implemented the Facebook “remarketing pixel”. This involves code snippets that are able to identify your browser via the browser ID – your browser’s individual fingerprint – and detect that you visited our website and what exactly you viewed there. A direct connection to the Facebook servers is made when you visit our website. Facebook can identify you by your browser ID because it is linked to other data about you stored by Facebook on your user account. Facebook will then display custom ads from us, tailored to your needs, on your Facebook timeline or elsewhere on Facebook.

We at Thomann cannot personally identify you via the Facebook pixel, because we do not save personal data other than your browser ID using the Facebook remarketing pixel.  
More information about Facebook Custom Audiences, the particulars of data processing using this service and Facebook’s data policy can be found at [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

* * *

#### **Statutory right of withdrawal**

**You can find out how to withdraw your consent given using our cookie pop-up in the section _Withdrawal of consent to the use of cookies and other identifiers/tags._**

* * *

Meta Platforms Ireland Ltd. is a subsidiary of Meta Platforms, Inc., based in the USA. It cannot be excluded that the data collected by Facebook will also be sent to the USA.

#### **Google Ads Conversion Tracking**

Our website utilises the Google Ads Conversion Tracking function. The provider of this service is Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland (“Google”). If you click on an Ads advertisement placed by Google, a “conversion tracking cookie” will be stored on your computer. This cookie is valid for 30 days and does not contain data that would allow us to identify you personally.

Conversion tracking allows us and Google to identify the Ads advertisements you have clicked on and whether you were forwarded to our website via an advertisement, if you visit our website and the cookie is still valid. Google provides us with our own cookie, which is different from the cookies of other customers of this Google service, so that we can only implement a reach assessment with regard to our own cookies, and not across all websites of customers of the Google Ads service. The cookie enables us to compile our own conversion statistics on customers that visit our website through Ads advertisements.

* * *

#### **Statutory right of withdrawal**

**You can find out how to withdraw your consent given using our cookie pop-up in the section _Withdrawal of consent to the use of cookies and other identifiers/tags._**

* * *

Google Ireland Ltd. is a subsidiary of Google LLC, based in the USA. It cannot be excluded that the data collected by Google will also be sent to the USA.

You can find more information on how Google uses your data, how the various Google technologies work and Google's privacy policy at [https://business.safety.google/privacy/](https://business.safety.google/privacy/).

#### **Google Marketing Platform and Google Ads Remarketing**

Our website utilises Remarketing Services of the Google Marketing Platform and Google Ads Remarketing. The provider of both services is Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland (“Google”). Using these services, we can show you advertisements associated with our online shop (e.g. interesting product offers) on the websites of other service providers that also use these Google services (“partners” in the Google Display network). Furthermore, we can use Google Ads Remarketing to place a message on the websites of other providers in the Google Display Network reminding you to complete your order if you have recently abandoned an order on our online shop. This requires the use of cookie technology.

To this end, Google stores a small file containing a sequence of numbers (“cookie ID”) in your browser to identify you as a visitor to our website and collect other anonymous data about the use of our website. The cookie ID is stored by us and used only to explicitly identify your browser and not to identify you as a person. These services are not used to collect or store your personal data.

We use Google Remarketing across multiple devices. This means, for example, that if you begin making a purchase from our online shop using your smartphone and complete it on your laptop, we can reach you with the abovementioned personalised advertisements on the other device you use. However, this will only happen if you have given Google your consent for Google to link your web and app browsing history with your Google account, and for information from your Google account to be used to personalise the advertisements you see online. In this instance, Google uses the data of this logged-in user together with Google analytics data to define and create audience lists for Remarketing across multiple devices. Google Analytics collects this user’s Google-authenticated IDs to support this function. This data from Google is temporarily linked with our Google Analytics data to create our audiences.

Please check the privacy settings in your Google account to prevent Google linking your web and app browsing history with your Google account.

No personal data will be transmitted to Google for the purpose of displaying a message reminding you of an abandoned order on our online shop. Only the fact that you wanted to place an order on our online shop under the collected cookie ID and abandoned this order, as well as the total price of the intended order, will be transmitted to Google for this purpose (“shopping cart transfer”).

* * *

#### **Statutory right of withdrawal**

**You can find out how to withdraw your consent given using our cookie pop-up in the section _Withdrawal of consent to the use of cookies and other identifiers/tags._**

* * *

Google Ireland Ltd. is a subsidiary of Google LLC, based in the USA. It cannot be excluded that the data collected by Google will also be sent to the USA.

Further information about Google’s remarketing services, the details of data processing through these services and Google’s privacy policy can be found under [http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) as also as under [https://business.safety.google/privacy/](https://business.safety.google/privacy/).

#### **Bing Ads**

Our website uses “Bing Ads” remarketing technology, provided by Microsoft Ireland Operations Limited, One Microsoft Place, South County Business Park, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, D18 P521, Ireland (“Microsoft”). If you access our website via a Microsoft Bing advertisement, Microsoft places a cookie on your computer (“conversion cookie”). This enables Microsoft and Bing Ads customers to identify that the advertisement has been clicked and a user has been forwarded to our website. In this way, it is possible to address you once again with targeted product recommendations and interest-based advertising on Microsoft’s websites and the websites of other “Bing Ads” customers.  
  
The information collected using the conversion cookie serves to create conversion statistics. We learn the total number of users who have clicked on a Microsoft Bing advertisement and thus been forwarded to our website. Other anonymous data (e.g. the number of page views and the length of time spent on the website) is also collected. We do not receive information that would allow us to identify users personally.

* * *

#### **Statutory right of withdrawal**

**You can find out how to withdraw your consent given using our cookie pop-up in the section _Withdrawal of consent to the use of cookies and other identifiers/tags._**

* * *

Microsoft Ireland Operations Limited is a subsidiary of the Microsoft Corporation, based in the USA. It cannot be excluded that the data collected by Microsoft will also be sent to the USA.

Further information about Microsoft’s ad services, the details of data processing through these services and Microsoft’s privacy policy can be found under [https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-GB/](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-GB/).

#### **TikTok pixel**

Our website uses remarketing technology provided by TikTok Technology Limited, 10 Earlsfort Terrace, Dublin, D02 T380, Ireland (“TikTok”). To this end we have implemented the TikTok remarketing pixel (“TikTok pixel”) on our website. A direct connection to the TikTok servers is made via the TikTok pixel when you visit our website. TikTok can identify you by your browser ID because it is linked to other data about you stored by TikTok on your user account. TikTok will then display custom ads from us, tailored to your needs, on your TikTok page or elsewhere on TikTok.

We at Thomann cannot personally identify you via the TikTok pixel, because we do not save personal data other than your browser ID using the TikTok pixel. The information collected via the TikTok pixel enables us to generate conversion statistics. We learn the total number of users who have clicked on a TikTok advertisement and thus been forwarded to our website. Other anonymous data (e.g. the number of page views and the length of time spent on the website) is also collected. We do not receive information that would allow us to identify users personally.

More information about the TikTok pixel, the particulars of data processing using this service and TikTok’s privacy policy can be found at [https://www.tiktok.com/legal/privacy-policy-eea?lang=en](https://www.tiktok.com/legal/privacy-policy-eea?lang=en) and [https://ads.tiktok.com/i18n/official/policy/controller-to-controller.](https://ads.tiktok.com/i18n/official/policy/controller-to-controller)

TikTok also processes your personal data in the USA. Please also note that the transfer of your data to TikTok’s Chinese parent company based in China and other TikTok partners who are also not based in the EU is not excluded.

* * *

#### **Statutory right of withdrawal**

**You can find out how to withdraw your consent given using our cookie pop-up in the section _Withdrawal of consent to the use of cookies and other identifiers/tags._**

* * *

#### **Pinterest pixel (Pinterest tag)**

Our website uses the Pinterest pixel or Pinterest tag for remarketing purposes, a service of Pinterest Europe Ltd, Palmerston House, 2nd Floor, Fenian Street, Dublin 2, Ireland (“Pinterest”). With the help of this service we can target you with advertising by showing Pinterest ads to visitors to our website when you visit the social network Pinterest.

To this end we have implemented Pinterest tags and the Pinterest pixel on our website. A direct connection to the Pinterest servers is made when you visit our website. Pinterest can identify you by your browser ID because it is linked to other data about you stored by Pinterest on your user account. Pinterest will then display custom ads from us, tailored to your needs, on your Pinterest profile page or elsewhere on Pinterest.

We at Thomann cannot personally identify you via the Pinterest pixel, because we do not save personal data other than your browser ID using the Pinterest pixel.

We use remarketing via the Pinterest pixel across multiple devices. This means, for example, that if you begin making a purchase from our online shop using your smartphone and complete it on your laptop, we can reach you with the abovementioned personalised advertisements on the other device you use.

More information about the Pinterest pixel, the particulars of data processing using this service and Pinterest’s privacy policy can be found at [https://policy.pinterest.com/en-gb/privacy-policy.](https://policy.pinterest.com/de/privacy-policy)

* * *

#### **Statutory right of withdrawal**

**You can find out how to withdraw your consent given using our cookie pop-up in the section _Withdrawal of consent to the use of cookies and other identifiers/tags._**

* * *

#### **Snap pixel**

We use remarketing technology provided by Snap Inc., 772 Donald Douglas Loop North, Santa Monica, CA 90405, USA (“Snap”). To this end we have implemented the Snap remarketing pixel (“Snap pixel”) on our website. A direct connection to the Snap servers is made via the Snap pixel when you visit our website. Snap can identify you by your browser ID because it is linked to other data about you stored by Snap on your user account. Snap will then display custom ads from us, tailored to your needs, on the Snap social network.

We at Thomann cannot personally identify you via the Snap pixel, because we do not save personal data other than your browser ID using the Snap pixel. The information collected via the Snap pixel enables us to generate conversion statistics. We learn the total number of users who have clicked on a Snap advertisement and thus been forwarded to our website. Other anonymous data (e.g. the number of page views and the length of time spent on the website) is also collected. We do not receive information that would allow us to identify users personally.

More information about the Snap pixel, the particulars of data processing using this service and Snap ’s privacy policy can be found at [https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/privacy-policy](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/privacy-policy) and [https://businesshelp.snapchat.com/s/article/snap-pixel-faq?language=en\_US](https://businesshelp.snapchat.com/s/article/snap-pixel-faq?language=en_US)[.](https://ads.tiktok.com/i18n/official/policy/controller-to-controller)

* * *

#### **Statutory right of withdrawal**

**You can find out how to withdraw your consent given using our cookie pop-up in the section _Withdrawal of consent to the use of cookies and other identifiers/tags._**

* * *

#### **Adform**

Our website utilises services for the purposes of retargeting and conversion tracking. The provider of these services is Adform A/S, Wildersgade 10B, 1. sal. 1408 Copenhagen, Denmark (“Adform”). Using the Ad Serving service, we can show you advertisements associated with our online shop (e.g. interesting product offers) on the websites of other service providers that also use Adform. Ad Serving and the integrated conversion tracking function also enable us and Adform to identify the advertisements you have clicked on and whether you were forwarded to our website via an advertisement, if you visit our website.

To this end we have implemented the Adform pixel as an identifier. This involves code snippets that are able to identify your browser via the browser ID – your browser’s individual fingerprint – and detect that you visited our website and what exactly you viewed there. A direct connection to the Adform servers is made via the pixel when you visit our website. Adform processes the data collected by the pixel in order to provide the abovementioned services.

We at Thomann are not able to personally identify you via the Adform pixel, because we do not save personal data other than your browser ID using the Adform pixel.

* * *

#### **Statutory right of withdrawal**

**You can find out how to withdraw your consent given using our cookie pop-up in the section _Withdrawal of consent to the use of cookies and other identifiers/tags._**

* * *

Further information about Adform’s services, the details of data processing through these services and Adform’s privacy policy can be found at [https://site.adform.com/privacy-center/platform-privacy/product-and-services-privacy-policy/](https://site.adform.com/privacy-center/platform-privacy/product-and-services-privacy-policy/).

#### **Embedded YouTube videos**

When you visit a website into which YouTube videos are embedded, Google receives information that you have accessed this website. The data mentioned in the above section (“usage data”) is also transmitted. This happens regardless of whether Google provides a user account that you can log into or whether no user account exists. If you are logged into your Google account, your data will be directly associated with your account. If you do not wish data to be associated with your Google profile, you must log out prior to visiting websites into which YouTube videos are embedded.

Google stores this data as a user profile and uses it for purposes of advertising, market research and/or demand-led configuration of its website. Such evaluation takes place (even for users who are not logged in) for the purposes of demand-oriented advertising. You can find more information in the Google Privacy Policy: [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

The legal basis for the use of YouTube videos on our website is our legitimate interest (Article 6(1)(1)(f) GDPR) in the demand-oriented, visually optimised presentation of our website, above all through the use of videos.

* * *

#### **Right to object**

**You have the right to object to the creation of these user profiles, whereby you must contact Google in order to exercise this right. You can use the privacy settings in your Google account to determine how Google can use your data for advertising or other purposes. This includes settings determining the display of advertisements (“ads”).**

* * *

#### **Classified ads**

You can place classified ads on our website free of charge. To this end, we collect your name, address and email address in a registration form. These details will then be saved in our system and used for creating the classified ad. Either your name or a pseudonym, as well as your country, city, postal code and email address will be published in the classified ad. In addition, information regarding the description of the equipment, pictures uploaded by you and your telephone number (optional) will be part of the published classified ad.

The legal basis for the data processing is Article 6(1)(f) GDPR.

This is to enable interested parties to contact you, and to prevent fraud. Additionally, we compare the data provided by you for the placement of the classified ad with our customer database. This is to correct any false customer data, and to assign the classified ad to a customer account (if you are already a customer of Musikhaus Thomann). This enables you to comfortably administrate your classified ad via the regular Customer Centre log-in.

The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. This is the case for data collected during the registration process if the registration for our website is cancelled or modified.

As a user, you have the option to cancel your registration at any time. The data stored about you can be modified at any time via customer support. You must make a request to us for your customer account to be deleted. To do this, contact our customer support (for example, using the contact details of your personal contacts shown on the left in your customer account). Your personal data will only be blocked before deletion in individual cases if deletion prevents legal retention requirements or official orders.

####   
**Rights as a data subject**

If your personal data is processed, you are a data subject as defined in the GDPR and you have the following rights with regard to the controller:

**1\. Information, rectification, restriction and deletion**  
You have the right to access the data stored about you by Musikhaus Thomann, and about information concerning its origin, recipient and the purpose of data processing by Thomann’s websites free of charge at any time. In addition, you have the right to rectify, delete or restrict the processing of your personal data, provided the legal requirements to do so are met.

Details can be found in the relevant statutory provisions, Articles 15 to 19 GDPR.

**2\. Right to data portability**  
You have the right to receive the personal data concerning you that you have provided to Musikhaus Thomann as the controller, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. Musikhaus Thomann can comply with this right by providing a csv export of the customer data processed about you.

**3\. Right to information**  
If you have exercised your right to rectification, deletion or restriction of processing against the controller, the controller is obliged to notify all recipients to whom your personal data has been disclosed of this rectification or deletion of data or restriction of processing, unless this proves to be impossible or involves a disproportionate effort.

You have the right to be informed about these recipients by the controller.

* * *

#### **4\. Right to object**

**You have the right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, at any time to the processing of personal data concerning you that is based upon point (e) or (f) of Article 6(1) GDPR, including profiling based upon those provisions.**

**The controller shall no longer process the personal data concerning you unless the controller demonstrates compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.**

**Where your personal data is processed for direct marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time to the processing of personal data concerning you for such marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing.**

**If you object to processing for direct marketing purposes, your personal data will no longer be processed for such purposes.**

**In the context of the use of information society services, and notwithstanding Directive 2002/58/EC, you may exercise your right to object by automated means using technical specifications.**

* * *

**5\. Revocability of declarations of consent under data protection law**

You may also revoke your consent with regard to Musikhaus Thomann at any time with effect for the future using the contact details given below.

**6\. Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority**  
Without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement if you consider that the processing of personal data relating to you infringes the GDPR.

The supervisory authority with which the complaint has been lodged will inform the complainant on the progress and the outcome of the complaint including the possibility of a judicial remedy pursuant to Article 78 GDPR.

####   
**Updates to this Privacy Notice**

Musikhaus Thomann may update this Privacy Notice from time to time. Any changes will be displayed on the website. If you have any comments or questions regarding this Privacy Notice or any other guidelines on this website, please contact us in writing.

12/2024

This is how you can reach us
----------------------------

#### Do you like what you're seeing?

Share Share Email Give Feedback

Your Feedback

### Thomann Newsletter

Don't miss anything ever again with our Newsletter!

* check Inspirational contributions
* check Deals
* check Thomann Insights

By clicking on "Sign up now", you agree to receiving e-mail advertising. You can unsubscribe at any time. You can find further information on the newsletter in our [data protection guideline](https://www.thomannmusic.com/compinfo_privacy.html#privacy_newsletter).

#### Shop and pay safely

Payment can be made safely and securely with PayPal, Amazon Pay, Credit Card or Bank Transfer.

#### Your benefits

#### Service

* [Terms & Conditions](https://www.thomann.de/intl/compinfo_terms.html) / [Imprint](https://www.thomann.de/intl/compinfo_imprint.html)
* Cookie Settings

© 1996–2024 Thomann GmbH. Thomann loves you, because you rock!
